<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://example.org/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://example.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://example.org/home/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/home/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My name is John Moody. This is a site for my projects and whatnot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently made &lt;a href=&#34;https://jcm93.github.io/jmc&#34;&gt;jmc&lt;/a&gt;, which I wrote after I graduated from college last summer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some stuff I&amp;rsquo;ve done:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://digitalccbeta.coloradocollege.edu/pid/coccc:25837&#34;&gt;High-Performance Persistent Graphs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://example.org/jmc/&#34;&gt;jmc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://tomcheavens.photos&#34;&gt;Tom Cheavens Photography&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contact:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;john [.] moody [@] coloradocollege [.] edu&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Money!</title>
      <link>http://example.org/money/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/money/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a recent college graduate, and I don&amp;rsquo;t currently have a job. If you have the means, please consider sending me some cash. It would strongly encourage me to spend more time on jmc and other neat projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.paypal.me/jcm93/10&#34;&gt;PayPal&lt;/a&gt; | [Venmo]((&lt;a href=&#34;https://venmo.com/johnmoody&#34;&gt;https://venmo.com/johnmoody&lt;/a&gt;) | &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.coinbase.com/jcm93&#34;&gt;Bitcoin&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;https://cash.me/$jcm93/10&#34;&gt;Square&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My email is john [.] moody [@] coloradocollege [.] edu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks very much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://example.org/jmc/&#34;&gt;Back to jmc&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;http://example.org/&#34;&gt;Home&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jmc</title>
      <link>http://example.org/jmc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/jmc/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jcm93/jmc/&#34;&gt;(on Github)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;jmc is a new media player project with the simple goal of being the best tool for organizing and listening to music on macOS, period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/8NhiZpE.png&#34; alt=&#34;screenshot&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;jmc wants to bring power, flexibility and elegance back to macOS media management, and rescue macOS from iTunes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;jmc is also a completely open-source project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;table-of-contents&#34;&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#features&#34;&gt;Features&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#roadmap&#34;&gt;Roadmap&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#download&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;features&#34;&gt;Features&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;jmc aims to be a simple, elegant and powerful application for managing media on macOS. It is modeled after early versions of iTunes, reintroducing a persistent album art view and providing a functional user interface. The entire interface is geared toward intuitiveness, efficiency, and performance, particularly for large music libraries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;advanced-search&#34;&gt;Advanced Search&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/oYB83zF.png&#34; alt=&#34;screenshot&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The powerful advanced search filter offers the ability to explore your library and create smart playlists, all without leaving the library view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;shared-libraries&#34;&gt;Shared Libraries&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;jmc implements shared libraries the way you&amp;rsquo;ve always wanted them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;jmc can connect to other nearby instances of itself, displaying their libraries in the source list. Macs running jmc can connect to each other using either infrastructure or peer-to-peer Wi-Fi (clients in close physical proximity on different networks). You can either stream music from a shared library, or drag and drop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/SJ5RgM5.png&#34; alt=&#34;screenshot&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soon, jmc will be able to run in a persistent server-only mode, allowing you to access your music from anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;roadmap&#34;&gt;Roadmap&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The current build of jmc is a pared-down, minimal music organizer and player. For jmc to compete with features in state-of-the-art media managers on other platforms like auto-tagging and custom fields, more work is yet to be done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Future versions of jmc will likely integrate with &lt;a href=&#34;http://beets.io/&#34;&gt;beets&lt;/a&gt;, to provide auto-tagging and album artwork fetching, support for multiple pieces of album artwork, custom fields for tracks, and more. To integrate with beets, jmc will migrate away from its current persistence framework (Core Data) in favor of SQLite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;jmc also wants to support a persistent background server mode of operation, to allow users to remotely connect to their libraries from beyond the local area network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other features that need implementation on jmc right now also include, in descending order of triviality:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Non-placeholder icons.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advanced playback features like crossfades, custom start/stop playback positions, custom volume settings for tracks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Making shared libraries better and less crash-prone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Location manager that offers a functional interface for managing where jmc thinks media files are. This is a large component of what will make jmc nice to use for external libraries. High priority.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FLAC support. Currently jmc uses &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.apple.com/reference/avfoundation/avaudioengine&#34;&gt;AVAudioEngine&lt;/a&gt; for audio playback. I am currently investigating solutions here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fancier views for media akin to the iTunes album and artist views (but which aren&amp;rsquo;t broken).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A discrete, GUI-less build of jmc that will run as a persistently available media server for jmc clients on the local area network, and beyond.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Miscellany:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Podcast/video support.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AppleScript support.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Last.fm integration?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a MiniPlayer!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;download&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, please consider &lt;a href=&#34;http://example.org/money/&#34;&gt;supporting development by feeding me with your money&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The code for jmc is available &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jcm93/jmc/&#34;&gt;on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;. The latest stable binary can be found in the releases tab.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Future versions of jmc will likely be distributed through the App Store, to simplify the process of versioning and distribution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in helping to create a better future for macOS media management, &lt;a href=&#34;http://example.org/&#34;&gt;drop me a line&lt;/a&gt; and come get involved!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jmc Roadmap</title>
      <link>http://example.org/jmc/roadmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/jmc/roadmap/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few high priorities for jmc features are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support for multiple pieces of album artwork per album, including PDFs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More thorough, and preferably automatically tagged metadata.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Custom fields for media (think &amp;ldquo;featuring&amp;rdquo;, or &amp;ldquo;mood&amp;rdquo;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While some of these features were half-written and planned for the current release, I realized that the best way to support them would likely be to introduce compatibility with the &lt;a href=&#34;http://beets.io/&#34;&gt;beets&lt;/a&gt; project, which is already a wonderful media management system for macOS users that supports auto-tagging, artwork management and much more. Since supporting beets will involve migrating from jmc&amp;rsquo;s current persistence framework (Core Data) toward SQLite, I elected not to complete half-baked versions of the above, only to rewrite large swaths of them later on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: this upcoming migration has the side effect that subsequent versions of jmc will probably require you to re-import your library.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some simple features that need implementation on jmc right now include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Non-placeholder icons.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A location manager that offers a pleasant interface for viewing and manipulating where jmc thinks media files are. Also, media directory monitoring using FSEvents to watch directories for changes that warrant metadata modification to application entities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advanced playback features like crossfades, custom start-stop playback positions and volume settings for tracks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few slightly larger things:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fancier views for media akin to the iTunes album and artist views (but which aren&amp;rsquo;t broken).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FLAC support. Currently jmc uses &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.apple.com/reference/avfoundation/avaudioengine&#34;&gt;AVAudioEngine&lt;/a&gt; for audio playback. I am currently investigating solutions here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A discrete, server-only version of jmc that runs in the background and serves media from a volume to jmc clients on a local area network, and beyond (think Plex). This is basically jmc minus the GUI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A better way of displaying and adding these “probably-always-available” remote libraries other than the Shared Libraries tab of the source list.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Making shared libraries better and less crash-prone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still more stuff:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make jmc Applescript-able&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Last.fm integration? Last.fm seems to be on its way out, but there are few alternatives.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A MiniPlayer!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, jmc currently doesn&amp;rsquo;t play podcasts or videos. This functionality will likely arrive in some capacity in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://example.org/jmc/&#34;&gt;Back to jmc&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;http://example.org/&#34;&gt;Home&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>